Deep in the heart of the Aegean lies the island of Navarone.
纳瓦隆岛位于爱琴海中心深处。
In 1943, it stood lik e a thorn in the Allied side.
1943年，对盟军方面来说，它就象一根刺扎在那里。
Newly designed radar-controlled guns set in the heart of the ancient rock...
新近安装在岩洞里由雷达控制的巨炮……
...gave the German High Command total strategic dominance.
……使德国最高统帅部获得了总体战略上的优势。
Air strik es and naval attacks had proven costly and ineffective.
空军轰炸和海军攻击已被证明是代价巨大而无效的。
In desperation, the Allies turned to infiltration.
无奈之下，盟军转而采用渗透的方式。
On the night of September the 24th, a specially trained commando group...
9月24日夜，一支经过特殊训练的突击队……
...succeeded in penetrating the very heart of the gun complex...
……成功潜入巨炮阵地内部……
...planted explosives at the base of the giant shell hoists...
……在巨炮底座安放了炸药……
...then withdrew to await rescue by ships of the Royal Navy.
……然后撤离并等待英国皇家海军军舰的救援。
- Reduce speed, number one. - Aye, aye, sir. Down 50 reps.
- 减速。 - 是，长官，降至半速。
Fire!
开火！
Move! Move!
快！快！
Come on, move it!
赶快！快！
Move it!
快!
Move it, move it, move it, move it!
快，快，快，快！
Regulations state, sir, that in the absence of bacon, ham, et cetera...
条例规定，长官，当没有熏肉、火腿，等等时……
...the acting catering officer, that's you, sir...
……作为饮食供应官解决这个问题的办法，先生……
...shall authorize once per week, the issue of offal.
……应该每周供应一次下水。
- Offal? - Offal, sir...
- 下水? - 下水， 长官……
...is kidneys, liver, tongue, brains...
……比如腰子、肝、口条、脑子……
Well, I'll be damned!
哦，该死的！
- Milly, how nice to see you! - Hello, sir.
- 米勒，很高兴见到你！ - 你好，长官.
- Whatever are you doing here? - I've no idea.
- 你正忙些什么？ - 无所事事。
I'm reporting to Cmdr. Jensen.
我正要向延森司令官报到。
I gather you've been hurling yourself over the white cliffs. How's the leg?
听说你从峭壁上掉下来摔伤了。腿怎样了？
It's in the same place. I thought they pensioned you off for good.
- 至少我还能走。 - 我本以为他们会给你发养老金让你退休。
You still peddling those whiz-bangs of yours?
你还在干老本行？
Yes, we've got things that go boom for all occasions.
是的，我们已经搞到一些能让某些场合热闹非凡的玩意。
I'm working with a new detonator. It's interesting...
我正在和一些新型雷管一起干活，有趣极了！
Excuse me, sir. We can't keep Cmdr. Jensen waiting.
对不起，长官，最好不要让延森司令官久等。
- We'll have a quiet pint later on. - He'd like to see you too, together.
- 晚些时候一起喝一杯。 - 他也希望一起见到你。
Corporal, put that in my office, will you?
下士，把这放到我办公室好吗？
Mallory.
马勒瑞。
Take a pew. How's the leg?
拿把椅子。腿怎样了？
- And Miller, isn't it? - Yes, sir.
- 还有米勒，是吧？ - 是的，长官。
Hear you've been attached to Winston's toy shop.
听说你加入了温斯顿的“玩具店”？
"Department of Dirty Tricks" as the Whitehall chaps call it.
“诡计的一部分”，白宫的那个家伙说的。
Well, they speak very well of you.
他们对你评价很高。
Right. We need you chaps for something rather special.
是的，我们需要像你这种有特殊才能的人。
I'm afraid it's not exactly a masterpiece...
这不是一张很清晰的照片……
...but I wonder if you can identify this fellow.
……但如果你能认出这个家伙，还是会让我吃惊的。
Think back to Navarone.
回想一下纳瓦隆。
I'd rather not, sir.
我实在想不起来，长官。
Nicolai?
纳瓦隆？
Yes. Let you down a bit, didn't he?
怎么样，有点印象了吧？
But what about him?
他怎样？
Andrea's people had him shot as a traitor, didn't they?
希腊方面安德里亚的人把他当叛徒枪毙了，是吧？
Yes, so we were told.
是的，我们也被告知了。
In fact, he escaped.
实际上，他逃走了。
He wasn't a traitor. He was a German agent...
他不是个叛徒。他是一个德国间谍……
...who we believe is operating now in Yugoslavia with the Partisans...
……我们相信他正在南斯拉夫和当地的游击队在一起……
...posing as one Capt. Lescovar.
……化名是莱斯卡瓦上尉。
Now, you both knew Nicolai.
现在，你们两人知道了纳瓦隆方面的情况。
In fact, you're the only people we know of can make a positive identification.
实际上，你们是我们所知的唯一能搞清真相的人。
So I'd like you to go out there and cope.
所以，我想让你们回到那里妥善处理此事。
Cope, sir?
妥善处理，长官？
Kill him.
杀了他。
Discreetly, if possible.
严格地说，如果可能的话。
But I'm a civilian now, sir.
但是，我现在是个平民，长官。
Yes, we thought about that.
是的，我们考虑过这个。
So you've been recalled to the current and promoted.
所以，你被招回并因此而获晋升为……
Staff sergeant.
……中士。
Awfully generous, sir.
非常慷慨，长官。
Exactly how do we get there?
我们怎样去做？
We're tacking you onto Force 10.
你们将隶属于第十突击队。
The code name for an operation for the Allied mission in Yugoslavia.
这是一个在南斯拉夫进行联合行动的部队的代号。
Excuse me, sir. What's their objective?
对不起，长官。这个突击队的任务目标是什么？
It's being treated on a need-to-know basis.
这是保密的。
And you don't need to know.
而且你不需要知道。
Barnsby, come in.
巴纳比，进来。
- Sir? - Colonel.
- 长官？ - 上校。
Force 10 flies out tonight.
第十突击队今晚出发。
Oh, that's all right. Taking these boys with you.
好了，这些人归你调遣。
I beg your pardon, sir?
对不起，请重说一遍，长官。
It's a matter of transportation. You've got passengers.
你只是顺便捎上他们，他们是你的乘客。
Just a sideshow. This is Maj. Mallory, Sgt. Miller.
仅仅搭便车而已。这是马勒瑞少校，米勒中士。
Lt. Col. Barnsby.
巴纳比陆军上校。
Sir, my mission is all set. It's been planned down to the last detail.
长官，我的任务准备好了，最后的细节也计划好了。
The last thing we need are a couple of passengers.
我们恐怕不方便捎带乘客。
Maj. Mallory does have a certain amount of experience.
马勒瑞少校在这方面有相当的经验。
I wouldn't doubt it.
我当然相信。
We're talking about some hard travelling, sir.
我们要进行的可是一次危险的旅行，长官。
We've gotta move fast. My men are young, in top physical shape.
我们得行动迅速，我的人都很年轻，而且身体状态良好。
- They're specially trained for this. - I'm aware of that.
- 他们已经为这次任务接受了特殊的训练。 - 我知道这一点。
Sir, I am concerned about the safety of my command.
长官，我要考虑这次行动的安全性。
Well, these chaps have got a job to do as well.
好了，这些家伙有他们自己的任务。
And it's up to you to deliver them safely to the Partisans.
你只要把他们安全地交到当地游击队的手中。
And you leave for Italy at 2300 hours...
你们23：00出发去意大利……
...and you take off for Yugoslavia the following night.
……第二天晚上你们从那儿飞往南斯拉夫。
Very well, sir.
好的，长官。
Thank you. That's all, gentlemen.
谢谢，就这样吧，先生们。
Well, we'll do our best not to make a nuisance of ourselves, colonel.
我们会尽最大努力不给我们自己增加麻烦，上校。
All right, enough!
好的，这就足够了。
- Thought we were going to an airfield. - From what I've observed of Barnsby...
- 我们正去飞机场。 - 我从巴纳比上校身上感觉到……
...we might be going to Yugoslavia by walking on water.
……我们可能走水路去南斯拉夫。
All right, it's right along here. Slow down, Nolan.
对，沿着这条路走是正确的。慢一点，诺兰。
Stop it.
停下。
Nolan, kill the lights. All right, out.
- 诺兰, 关灯。 - 好的，关了。
Oberstein, Reynolds, the fence.
奥波斯坦，雷诺兹，铁丝网。
You're gonna miss your plane unless you join us now, major.
少校，你要误飞机了，除非你现在就和我们一起走。
Remarkable way of getting on an aircraft, don't you think so?
这样上飞机真是不同寻常，你不这样认为吗？
Oh, well, nothing's ever easy, is it?
哦，是呀。万事开头难，对吧？
It's not easy if you insist on climbing through fences in the dark...
如果你在黑夜里爬过铁丝网，那就更不容易了……
...when there's a perfectly good gate half a mile up the road.
……尤其当半英里远处还有一扇非常漂亮的门的时候。
Anything we can do to help?
我们能帮什么忙吗？
Yeah, you can keep quiet and out of the way, major.
是的，少校，你可以保持安静，并离开那条路。
I don't have a lot of time for explanations.
我没有很多时间向你们解释。
One thing that you don't know...
有一件事你们是不知道的……
...is the last three Allied missions into Yugoslavia...
……必须去南斯拉夫和先头到达的3个联络员碰头……
...were blown right here in Italy.
……但他们在意大利被捕了。
So this time when we fly out, we're not advertising the fact to anybody.
我们这次出发，不能让任何人知道实情。
Holy cow, will you look at those guys!
天啊，你看到那些家伙了吗？
They're stealing half the field.
他们正在大偷特偷。
All right, hold it.
好，制住他们。
Wait for me.
都别乱动。
Okay, men, let's go!
好，伙计们，上吧！
- Blake, take care of Rastus there. - Yes, sir.
- 布莱克，在这好好照顾这个混蛋。 - 是，长官。
Okay, fellas, freeze.
好了，都站住，别动。
Back off. Come on, get back.
站好，快站好！
And you, back, back!
你，站好，站好！
Bill, Eddie, fetch those other guys out of there.
比尔，埃迪，把其他人抓回来。
What's your name, kid?
你叫什么名字，小子？
Walter.
沃尔特。
What's yours?
你想怎样？
Well, it sure in the hell ain't Rastus.
哦，我要告诉你我不是混蛋。
Walter.
沃尔特。
Good evening.
晚上好。
Major, move!
少校，走！
- You two guys officers? - More or less, yes.
- 你们俩是长官？ - 或许吧。
We're very much obliged to you, sergeant.
我很乐意给你们帮忙，中士。
- Weaver. - Oh, Sgt. Weaver. Thank you.
- 维沃. - 哦，维沃中士，谢谢！
U.S. Army Medical Corps.
美军卫生兵。
- But, sir! - All set, colonel.
- 我说，长官！ - 都搞定了，上校。
- Still stuff outside? - Yeah.
- 把他留下吗？ - 对。
- Okay, Oberstein? - Fine.
- 奥波斯坦? - 好的。
Hey, sir!
嗨，长官！
Where's Nolan?
诺兰在哪？
I think you can take it he won't be joining us.
我想你可以带上他，让他加入我们。
Okay, let's go.
好了，走！
You son of a bitch! I saved your asses back there...
你这个恶棍！我在那儿救了你们这些混蛋……
...and you run out on me.
……而你们却想把我扔下！
Hey, who is this guy? Get out of here.
嗨，这家伙是谁？从这滚开。
Hey, man, don't push! Don't push me!
嗨，伙计，别推！别推我！
- Look, you! - I think it's a bit late for that now.
- 你看！ - 我觉得现在有点晚了。
Look, you just shouldn't have left me there. I saved you bums.
看，你们刚才不该把我留在那儿。我救了你们。
Well, we didn't think you'd like where we're going.
好吧，我们不认为你会喜欢我们要去的地方。
You let me worry about that, huh?
嘿，你以为我会害怕？
That guy's gonna melt into the landscape.
那个家伙还以为我们是去观光呢。
Yeah, them Partisans are gonna think they've been invaded by Zulus.
是啊，那他只好等着去挨揍了。
Well, you are one man short.
好呀，你真是个不识时务的人！
Well, Nolan can handle a chute, at least.
好吧，到时候，诺兰至少能给你个降落伞。
- Can you handle a chute? - I can learn on the job.
- 你会跳伞吗？ - 我可以在跳的时候学。
That's right, you learn on the way down.
好极了，那你就在往下掉的路上学吧。
I'd better go tell the colonel we got us another passenger.
我最好告诉上校我们有了另一个乘客。
I think the colonel's got enough on his plate for the moment, don't you?
我认为上校此时有好多事情在做，你觉得呢？
So sorry.
借光。
I was rather hoping we'd lost that.
我们真应该把这个箱子扔掉。
You never know. It might come in useful.
你压根就不知道，它可有大用场。
Hey, hey, what do you got in there?
喂，喂，你在搞什么？
My pyjamas.
找我的睡衣。
Looks like high-explosive pyjamas to me.
当然，是会剧烈爆炸的睡衣。
Not to worry, old boy.
别担心，老伙计。
Been handling this since I blew up the nursery with my first chemistry set.
自从这玩意“出生”之日起，我就在照顾它了。
Poor old nanny.
我是一个可怜的老保姆。
We got company.
我们有伙伴了。
Cut two!
二号引擎被击中了！
Reynolds, bail out!
雷诺兹，让大伙跳伞！
Jump!
跳！
Go!
走！
Come on, move it!
快呀，走！
Come on, get out!
快出去！
Come on, move!
走呀！
Come on!
快！
Mallory.
马勒瑞。
Okay.
好的。
- Seen any of the others? - Not yet. Get down!
- 看到其他人了吗？ - 还没有。低下！
Come on.
走！
- Okay, Reynolds? - Yeah.
- 好，雷诺兹? - 在。
Where's your Sgt. Miller?
米勒中士在哪儿？
How the hell did he get here?
老天，他怎么会在那里？
You let him on the plane?
你们让他上飞机了？
I think he more or less invited himself.
也许是他自己来的。
- Where did you learn to use a knife? - Harvard University, man.
- 你在哪里学会用飞刀的？ - 在哈佛大学，长官。
You don't call him man. You call him sir, and you call me sir.
你不能称他“长官”，应叫他“先生”，应该称我为“长官”。
And as long as you're here, you do as you're told. Understood, soldier?
既然你在这里，你就要服从命令。懂吗，士兵？
Yes, sir.
是的，长官！
We've gotta get out of here before that patrol comes back.
在德军搜寻队回来之前，我们必须离开这里。
Lt. Reynolds, take point. Sgt. Weaver, bring up the rear.
雷诺兹, 你打头。 维沃, 殿后！
And everybody keep up. All right, let's go.
每个人都跟紧。好了，我们走。
Organized young gentleman, isn't he?
组织力高超的年轻绅士，对吧？
- Any idea where we are, colonel? - Not a hell of a lot, no.
- 上校，你认为我们应该向哪个方向走？ - 就是这个方向。
If we keep going east, we'll end up where we're supposed to.
我们继续往东走，就能到我们的目的地。
How did we get stuck with those two clowns?
我们怎么会和两个小丑在一起？
I don't know, Doug. Some idiot at British HQ.
不知道，没办法。英军司令部的白痴！
Come along, gentlemen. It's not teatime yet.
快点，先生们，还没有到喝下午茶的时间。
Do you think that young man has any idea where we are, Milly?
米勒，你认为那位年轻绅士清楚我们所在的位置吗?
- No, I shouldn't think so. - I shouldn't think so, either.
- 不，我想他不清楚。 - 我也是。
I'll go and try and find out.
我去问问他。
Yes, why don't you do that.
好呀，你为什么不去做呢？
Excuse me, colonel.
打扰了，上校。
Do you have any idea where we are?
你认为我们现在在哪儿？
I've got a good idea where we are.
我知道我们在哪儿。
And how long it's gonna take to get there, if you two can't keep up.
如果你们俩不跟紧，就不知道你们要在这里待多久了。
All right, let's move it.
好吧，咱们走吧。
- This is really beautiful country. - Yes, marvellous.
- 这真是一个美丽的国家。 - 是啊，不可思议。
Rather like the Scottish Highlands.
很像苏格兰高地。
- Do you know Scotland? - No.
- 你知道苏格兰吗？ - 不知道。
Yes.
当然。
I've often thought that I'd rather like to settle down there some day.
我经常想总有一天我会在那里定居下来。
Looks like you're gonna have to change your plans.
看起来你不得不改变打算了。
Take it easy.
放松。
Welcome.
欢迎。
Capt. Drazak.
德拉扎克上尉。
Seventeenth Partisan Regiment.
第十七游击队。
- Good morning, captain. - Welcome, welcome!
- 早上好，上尉！ - 欢迎，欢迎！
Thank you, Capt. Drazak.
谢谢，德拉扎克上尉。
They frightened you with bandages, huh?
他们头上缠着绷带的样子吓着你们了吧？
Without bandages you...
在头上缠上绷带……
German, how you say:
……德军……你说……
You say, "flamethrower."
……你说……我不知道怎么给你们说。
Yeah, yeah, flamethrower.
是的，当然，挺有趣的。
Hello! Hello!
你好！你好！
How do you do?
你好！
This is Maritza, good soldier comrade.
这是玛丽塔，优秀的战士。
How do you do, good soldier comrade?
你好，优秀的战士。
Hello, blackie.
你好，黑鬼！
Maybe it comes off now, Maritza.
也许我该把这层黑皮割下来，玛丽塔。
Back off, soldier.
住手，士兵！
I make big joke...
我开个玩笑……
...but joke on me.
……你也和我开玩笑。
Good, blackie. Come, we go. We eat with our comrades.
好吧，黑小子。来，我们走，和我的伙伴们一起吃饭去。
We make friends and drink. Then we fight the Germans.
我们交朋友、喝酒，然后打德国人。
Come.
来。
Come, we go.
来，我们走。
Where did you learn to punch like that? Harvard?
你在哪里学的象那样打人？哈佛大学吗？
No, Harlem. Colonel?
不是，在哈莱姆（哈莱姆――纽约的一个黑人聚住区）。上校？
I'm not trying to get anybody killed, least of all me.
我不想让任何人被杀，尤其是咱们的人。
- But that big idiot back there started it. - Just watch yourself, soldier.
- 但那个大白痴没安什么好心。 - 照顾好你自己就行了，士兵。
- How's the leg today? - It's much better, thank you.
- 今天你的腿怎样？ - 好多了，谢谢！
Good, good. Well, it looks like things may work out after all, huh?
好，好，看起来问题毕竟解决了，是吧？
Well, perhaps Miller and I can still carry out our little sideshow.
好，或许米勒和我能将我们的演出进行下去。
Sorry about Force 10.
我们对第十突击队的遭遇感到遗憾。
You're down to two men, aren't you?
你们剩下的人不多了。
Of course, I don't know what your mission was...
当然，我不知道你们的任务是什么……
...but obviously it just isn't on now, is it, colonel?
……但显然这个任务无法完成了，上校？
Looks rather like your own youngster, doesn't he?
他是不是很像你小时候？
Do you really think so?
你真的这么认为？
Please, come.
请，来吧！
Come, eat.
来，吃饭。
We are Chetniks...
我们是塞尔维亚民族解放军……
...not stinking Partisans.
……不是什么臭游击队。
We hunt Allied commandos like wild pigs!
我们像猎捕野猪一样捕捉抵抗者！
We work with Germans. They are our friends!
我们和德国人共事，他们是我们的朋友！
Good evening, gentlemen.
晚上好，先生们！
Maj. Schroeder, 11 th army corps.
施罗德少校，德国第十一集团军。
How do you do, major? Delighted to meet you.
你好，少校，见到你很高兴！
We thought these people were Partisans.
我们认为那些人是游击队员。
- Of all the luck, eh, Barnsby? - Sure.
- 幸亏他们不是，巴纳比？ - 当然。
Chetniks? Who would have believed that?
塞尔维亚民族解放军？谁会相信？
The other three Allied missions that fell into our hands...
你们的那三个联络员已经落到我们手里……
...were not quite so happy about it as you appear to be.
……你们的出现让我们更加高兴。
I'm not surprised, sir.
我不感到惊讶，先生。
But, you see, we're not commandos. We're deserters.
但是，你看，我们不是突击队，我们是逃亡者。
Deserters?
噢，逃亡者？
Give them to me, major. We kill them now.
把他们交给我，少校，我现在就杀了他们。
You see, we were in a prison camp in Termoli.
你看，我们被关在特摩利的监狱里。
We escaped.
我们逃了出来。
Managed to steal a plane. Flew here, RAF Lancaster.
想法偷了架飞机――英国皇家空军的兰开斯特轰炸机，飞到这里。
Were attacked, hit, bailed out and landed in your territory, thank God.
被你们的战斗机击中，我们跳伞落到你们的地盘上。感谢上帝！
Fascinating.
真有意思！
Tell me, why exactly did you desert?
告诉我，你们为什么逃亡？
Now, I'm glad you asked that.
我很高兴你问这个问题。
Yes.
是的。
Well, I am afraid that is rather a long story.
好吧，说起来话就长了。
Oh, please, you must not be afraid of boring me.
哦，说吧，你不必担心我会觉得烦。
Have you ever heard of penicillin?
你听说过青霉素吗？
No.
没听说。
Well, I'm not surprised. It's new.
当然，我不奇怪，那是一种新药。
It's a drug that prevents wounds from becoming infected.
是一种能治疗伤口感染的药。
It cures a whole range of infections...
它能治疗传染病……
...including some of the nastier social diseases.
……包括各种社会上的流行性传染病。
It's become one of the most sought-after items on the black market.
在黑市上，它是一种很抢手的紧俏货。
Our friend here, Sgt. Weaver of the American Medical Corps...
我们这位朋友，维沃中士，美军医疗特种兵……
...was our supplier.
……是我们的供货人。
You are saying you stole these drugs from the Army to sell to civilians?
你在说你们从军队偷了那些药卖给平民？
Not just to civilians, major. We'd sell it back to the Army.
不仅仅是平民，少校，我们还卖回给军队。
Any army.
任何军队。
I see.
我明白了。
Tell me, what has all this to do with that suitcase you keep looking at?
告诉我，你一直盯着看的手提箱是用来干什么的？
Well, that suitcase is full of our penicillin.
哦，那个手提箱里装满了青霉素。
Oh, indeed. Perhaps I could see some of it?
噢，是的。或许我能看一看？
Certainly, major.
当然可以，少校。
Open it, Miller.
打开箱子，米勒。
You can't do that here, you'd ruin the lot.
不能在这里打开，那会把青霉素给毁掉的。
You know perfectly well that any contamination will destroy it.
你知道任何污染都会毁坏青霉素的。
It must be opened under laboratory conditions.
箱子必须在实验室里才能打开。
There's nearly half a million pounds worth of stuff here.
这些东西可是价值50万英镑呀！
I know all that, but the major is not interested in our penicillin.
这些我都知道，但是少校对咱们的青霉素好象很感兴趣。
He only wants to know the truth.
他只是想知道真相。
What's the use of a half a million pounds to you out here?
你如果不能离开这里，你还能用那50万英镑吗？
Yes, well, that's beside the point, sir, but I'm not going to open it.
当然，可那是另外一回事，长官，我确实不能打开箱子。
Our story doesn't seem to convince you.
看来你不相信我们的故事。
No, it does not.
是的，不相信。
That's up to you, but every word he's told you is true.
那由你决定，但他告诉你的一切都是真的。
If you don't believe it, check with your intelligence.
如果你不相信，你可以去核实。
They'll verify the entire story.
然后，你就会相信我们说的每一件事。
Oh, I shall certainly verify your story.
哦，我当然会去核实的。
Every word of it.
核实每句话。
Get in!
进去！
Cute story, major, very cute.
有趣的故事，少校，非常有趣。
Now, what happens when they open the suitcase?
现在，当他们打开手提箱后会发生什么？
I should think we'll all get shot. Don't you, colonel?
我想我们全都会得到一颗子弹。你不这样认为吗，上校？
Headquarters acknowledges your signal.
总部查证了你的信息。
Thank you, Bauer.
谢谢，鲍尔。
Maritza...
玛丽塔……
...what do you think?
……你怎么认为？
They're lying.
他们在说谎。
What does it matter, anyway?
那又有什么关系？
Kill them.
杀了他们。
Yeah, you are probably right.
是呀，可能你是对的。
Do you know what I was thinking?
你知道我是怎么想的吗？
After the war, $1 million.
战争结束后，100万美元！
You, a simple peasant girl from where?
你，一个单纯的农家女孩，从哪里来的？
I can never pronounce the name of the place you come from.
我永远都搞不清你来的那个地方。
With so much money, we could...
有这么多钱，我们能……
They're lying.
他们在说谎！
Kill them.
杀了他们。
Out! Get out.
出来！滚出来！
What did I tell you?
我告诉你什么来着？
Well, at least we got a good night's sleep.
好啊，至少我们好好休息了一夜。
Good morning, gentlemen.
早上好，先生们！
Our intelligence confirms your escape from Italy.
我们的情报证实你们是从意大利逃走的。
You and you, follow me, please.
你，还有你，跟我来，请吧。
Your escape from Italy is one thing.
你们从意大利逃跑是一回事……
The rest of your story is something else.
……你们的故事以外的部分则是另一回事。
I had time to sleep on it.
我有足够的时间来琢磨你们所说的事。
So this morning, you know what I did?
所以，今天早上，你们知道我干什么了？
I opened the suitcase.
我打开了箱子。
Maritza!
玛丽塔！
And what do you think I found?
你们猜我发现了什么？
Firewood.
木柴。
What did you expect? We buried it before your Chetniks picked us up.
你期望发现什么？在你的塞尔维亚民族解放军 捉到我们之前，我们就把东西埋了。
We're not stupid. It's the only thing we've got to bargain with.
我们并不笨。这是我们唯一能和你讨价还价的东西。
That is what I thought you would say. I think you're lying.
我知道你们肯定会这么说的，但我想你们在撒谎。
You know they're lying. Why don't you let Drazak get rid of them?
你知道他们在说谎，为什么不让德拉扎克干掉他们？
Gently, Maritza.
冷静点，玛丽塔。
I don't believe your so-called penicillin exists, but it just might.
我不相信你们所说的青霉素存在，但也有可能真的存在。
So I will let you go and dig it up for me.
所以，我要你们去给我挖出来。
And if we do, you'll shoot us and bury us in the same hole.
如果我们按你说的去做，完事后你就会处死我们， 并把我们埋在同一个坑里。
I shall certainly shoot you if you don't.
如果你们不去，我倒是当然会枪毙你们。
Well, gentlemen, the choice is yours.
好了，先生们，你们只能做一个选择。
What I can't figure is how the firewood got in the case.
我无法想象的是木柴怎么会跑到箱子里。
Neither can I.
我也是。
Don't know where we're going to find any spare penicillin here, do you?
我不知道应该到哪儿去找那些青霉素，你呢？
What are we going to do, keep walking until we reach the Adriatic?
我们该怎么办？一直走，直到亚得里亚海？
I don't think the iron maiden will let us get that far.
我认为那个冷酷的小贱货不会让我们走那么远的。
Halt!
停下！
What did I tell you?
我告诉过你什么来着？
We are three miles past the spot where you were picked up.
我们已经走过你们被抓住的那个地方3英里了。
Well, where is this wonderful treasure?
那么，那些东西到底埋在哪儿呀？
In your imagination?
在你们的想象中？
No, ma'am, it's not in our imagination.
不，小姐，不在我们的想象中。
I think it's a bit further on, don't you?
我想应该还在稍远一点的地方，你觉得呢？
Yes, it is. Well, I mean, it's not much further than this.
是的，的确，离这里不太远了。
It's hard to tell, the whole country looks alike.
那很难说，这整个地方看起来都一个模样。
You will start digging within five minutes.
你们应该在5分钟内开始挖。
What if we haven't found it in five minutes?
如果我们在5分钟内没有找到怎么办？
Then you will be digging your graves.
那你们就挖自己的墓穴。
Hey, colonel.
嗨，上校。
Wait a minute, now this looks familiar.
等等，这里看起来有点眼熟。
Isn't this our little hollow down here?
这难道不是我们落下来时的那个洼地吗？
Yes, I think it is.
是的，我想是。
I remember this knoll over here. Ma'am, this is it.
我记得那边的那个小圆丘。小姐，就是这里。
I think this is it.
我想就是这里。
- This knoll over here? - Right.
- 这个小圆丘这边？ - 对。
You see, comrade, we lined it up between them...
你看，小姐，在它们之间某个地方……
There you are! There's our pile of stones.
在这！这不是那堆石头吗！
Gotta get them closer and we use the spades.
让他们靠近，我们用铁锨。
You take the two that are closest to you...
你对付离你最近的那两个……
...and I'll take the other one and the broad.
……我收拾另外两个。
I'm gonna get them closer now, okay?
我现在想法让他们靠近，好吗？
Fritz. Fritz, come! It's here.
当兵的，当兵的，过来！东西在这！
- Ready? - All right.
- 准备好了？ - 好了。
You can get up now. They're dead.
你们现在可以起来了。他们死了。
I put firewood in people's cases and hide their high explosives.
我把木柴放进了箱子里，也藏好了炸药。
Don't sit there gawping.
别坐在那里发呆了。
Get out of here. Keep moving in that direction.
离开这里，向那边跑吧。
Try to find Petrovitch's Partisans.
想办法找到彼特维彻的游击队。
Now, go.
现在，走。
Excuse me, good comrade soldier...
对不起，“优秀的战士”……
...but exactly what story are you gonna tell Schroeder about all this?
……但是，对这里发生的一切，你打算怎样对施罗德说呢？
You took us by surprise.
我自然有我自己的说法……
You got away.
……可以说你们跑掉了。
Here, hit me.
在这，打我。
Did you expect me to go back there with my hair combed?
你们指望我毫发无损地回去见施罗德吗？
Hit me!
打我。
Well, all right. I'm sorry.
那么，好吧，对不起啦。
Harder!
再用力些。
Come on, colonel.
走吧，上校。
I hope that man Schroeder believes that girl's story.
我希望那个施罗德相信女孩回去对他说的话。
If he doesn't believe her, he'd better think twice about calling her a liar.
如果他不信，他最好仔细想想还能再相信谁？
What about Miller and Reynolds?
米勒和雷诺兹怎么办？
What about them, colonel?
他们怎么办，上校？
Yes.
是呀。
I suppose they...
我猜他们……
Let's move it.
咱们走吧。
Do you have the feeling we're being followed?
你有没有感觉到我们被跟踪了？
About the last 10 minutes.
10分钟前我就发觉了。
Next time you can play the corpse.
下一次该你假扮死尸了。
Yeah, you seem pretty good with that thing, though.
但你枪法的确不错。
Could have been luck.
也许我不该打那么准。
- Germans? - Yes, or Drazak, I suppose.
- 德国人？ - 不象，或许是德拉扎克的人，我猜。
Partisans, thank God!
游击队。感谢上帝！
Good morning.
早上好！
What's the matter with him? We've been looking for you.
他怎么啦？我们一直在找你们。
Be quiet.
闭嘴。
You will make your report to Maj. Petrovitch.
你将向彼特维彻少校报告。
I think we've run into bad company, colonel.
我想我们遇上了一支糟糕的队伍，上校。
Yes, the leader.
是呀，瞧那个带头的。
- What about him? - Afraid I know him.
- 他怎么样？ - 恐怕我认识他。
- Nicolai. - Who the hell is Nicolai?
- 尼古拉。 - 尼古拉是谁？
It's Nicolai Lescovar.
他是尼古拉・莱斯卡瓦。
The man I was sent to kill.
我奉命杀死的那个人。
Dam, if it's the one I think it is. I know where we are.
水坝。如果我没搞错，我知道我们在哪里了。
So do I. Right in it.
是啊，我也明白了，正是我们要去的地方。
Do you think he's recognized you?
你认为他认出你了吗？
Yes, I think so.
我想是。
Lt. Col. Barnsby, United States Rangers.
巴纳比陆军上校。美军突击队。
Maj. Mallory, sir.
马勒瑞少校，先生。
You got away from the Germans.
你们从德国人那边来的。
How?
怎么回事？
We escaped.
我们逃出来的。
Capt. Lescovar has his doubts about that.
莱斯卡瓦上尉有些疑虑。
If you escaped, why were the Germans not pursuing you?
如果你们是逃出来的，为什么德国人没追捕你们？
We observed you for five miles before we picked you up.
在我们截住你们前，我们观察了你们5英里。
You should've observed that we killed two Chetniks that were following us.
你应该观察到我们杀了两个跟踪我们的塞尔维亚民族解放军的人。
- The men with the bandaged faces. - Exactly.
- 两个用绷带缠住脸的人？ - 完全正确。
Hardly a cause for congratulation. Those two men were Partisans.
不值得高兴，那两个人是游击队员。
Comrades of ours whom we had infiltrated into the Chetnik camp...
是我们潜入塞尔维亚民族解放军营地的同志……
...so now all links with our agent there are broken, thanks to you.
……所以，我们潜伏在敌人那里的特工的任务被你们破坏了， 真应该感谢你们。
I'm sorry.
对不起。
The fact remains that we're Allied officers.
事实上我们是盟军军官。
There's no reason we should be treated this way.
我们受到这种待遇是没有理由的。
I'm in command of Force 10. I insist that we be allowed...
我隶属于第十突击队，我坚持得到允许……
...to contact the Allied mission. I'm sure London informed you.
……去联系盟军联络官。我确信伦敦已经向你们通报了。
We are informed of many things by London...
我们得到伦敦的很多通报……
...very few of them ever seem to materialize.
……但很少是和实际一致的。
However, you are right.
不论怎样，你这回还是说对了。
I was informed of your mission.
关于你们的任务，我得到了通报。
Personally, I doubt if it was ever a practical one...
就个人而言，我怀疑如果真有这么回事……
...but now that you are here without equipment, the question is academic.
……但是你们没有任何装备，是不可能完成任务的。
And you, major, you came here as an observer, perhaps?
还有你，少校，你来这里或许是当观察员的吧？
No, sir.
不是，先生。
I was charged with a mission of my own.
我有我自己的任务。
It's confidential.
秘密任务。
Confidential!
机密！
Sometimes I get the impression...
有时，我有这样的印象……
...that London looks on this theatre of operations...
……伦敦方面看起来是把这里的战场……
...as a convenient place for conducting what they call "war games."
……当成一个很随意的搞所谓的“战争游戏”的地方。
- May I speak to you personally? - You are speaking to me personally.
- 我可以和你单独谈谈吗？ - 你正在和我一个人说话。
- I mean alone. - No.
- 我的意思是“单独”谈。 - 不。
The People's Army does not conduct military business in secret.
在我的军队里不会搞秘密勾当。
Very well, sir.
好极了，先生。
I was sent here to identify a German agent, code name Nicolai.
我被派到这里找出一个代号为尼古拉的德国间谍。
We are reliably informed...
我们确切地知道……
...that he has infiltrated the People's Resistance Army, and is now known...
……他已经潜入人民抵抗军内部，而且现在知道……
...as Capt. Lescovar.
这个人是莱斯卡瓦上尉。
And having identified this man, what were your further orders?
关于此人，你得到的命令是什么？
I was to eliminate him, sir.
清除他，先生。
- Eliminate. Don't you mean kill? - Yes, sir. I do mean kill.
- 清除？你是指杀了他？ - 是的，先生，是杀掉他。
Do you hear that, Lescovar?
你听到了，莱斯卡瓦？
The gentlemen from London want us to shoot you.
这位来自伦敦的绅士想让我们枪毙你。
I'm sorry, major.
很抱歉，少校。
I must admit you are indeed partly right.
我必须承认你说的有些方面确实正确。
There was an agent named Nicolai...
有一个代号为尼古拉的间谍……
...operating somewhere south of here and also calling himself Lescovar.
……在这个地区南部的某些地方活动，而且也自称莱斯卡瓦。
But he was identified many months ago. And eliminated.
但是，几个月前他被抓住，并被“清除”了。
The British were informed.
我们已经向英国通报了。
- But London were very specific, sir. - Yes, they frequently are specific...
- 但是，伦敦方面有不一样的看法，先生。 - 是的，他们总是有不一样的看法……
...and just as frequently wrong!
……而且经常是错的！
Lt. Marko, see that these gentlemen...
马可中尉，照顾好这些绅士们……
...give you a full report on their activities in the Chetnik camp.
……让他们就塞尔维亚民族解放军营地的情况写一个全面的报告。
A specific report.
一份特殊的报告。
Well, captain, I guess we owe you a bit of an apology, don't we?
上尉，我想我们应该向你道歉，不是吗？
Well, it happens. We all get badly briefed sometimes.
好了，没关系，我们都经常接到错误的情报。
Wish we had been briefed about the men with the bandages.
我们已经简要报告过那些头上缠着绷带的人情况了。
Replaced them with a couple of your own, that's a good trick.
用你们的人冒充他们，的确是一个很好的手法。
They were messengers to our agent at Schroeder's headquarters.
他们是我们在施罗德的司令部里的特工的信使。
Is your agent small, dark, pretty...
你们的特工就是那个小巧、黑皮肤、漂亮的……
...beautiful grey eyes and shoots from the hip?
……有着美丽的灰色眼睛和翘起的臀部的女孩？
You mean Maritza? Yes.
- 你指玛丽塔？ - 是的。
She took a big chance for us.
她为我们冒了很大的风险。
She isn't Petrovitch's daughter for nothing.
她是彼特维彻的女儿。
We hold this end of the bridge.
我们防守着桥的这头。
Over there, the Germans prepare for the final attack.
那边，德国人正在准备发动最后的进攻。
We have been ordered to prevent them crossing at all costs.
我们得到命令不惜一切代价阻止他们通过。
What exactly do they have over there?
他们在那边有多少部队？
Three divisions, perhaps more. We hold a brigade here.
三个师，也许更多。我们这儿有一个旅。
Soon they will bring up tanks, then...
很快，他们会出动坦克，然后……
- Why haven't you blown the bridge? - We have tried several times.
- 为什么你们不把桥炸掉？ - 我们试过几次。
Each time we lost valuable men.
每次我们都牺牲不少战士。
Maj. Petrovitch has decided it is impractical.
彼特维彻少校认为那样做不明智。
Well, he's wrong about that.
好了，他那样认为是错的。
There's no bridge in the world that can't be blown.
世上没有炸不毁的桥。
That's what Force 10 was here to prove.
这就是第十突击队来这里的目的。
I told you before, you have no men, you have no equipment.
我曾经提醒过你，你没有人手，也没有装备。
I can radio London for equipment. Get me an airstrip operational.
我可以发电报向伦敦要装备。你只需准备一个可用的简易机场。
Oh, call London, prepare an airstrip for a plane that may never arrive.
哦，呼叫伦敦，为一架可能根本不会到达的飞机准备一个简易机场。
- Have you anything else to suggest? - Yes.
- 你有什么其他好的建议吗？ - 是的。
Give me 20 men, I can blow that bridge to hell.
给我20个人，我能把这桥送下地狱。
You mean you can blow 20 of my men to hell, for nothing!
那意味着你能把我的20个人送进地狱，而不会有什么别的结果。
That bridge is indestructible.
这座桥是不可能被炸毁的。
Excuse me, sir, you don't need 20 men.
请原谅，长官，你不需要20个人。
You need Miller.
你只需要米勒。
- Miller? - He's an expert with explosives, sir.
- 米勒？ - 他是爆破专家，长官。
He's probably the best in England.
在英国，他可能是最优秀的。
- This Miller is in England? - No, sir.
- 这个米勒在英国？ - 不，先生。
- Prisoner in the Chetnik camp. - Then he's already dead.
- 他在塞尔维亚民族解放军营地的监狱里。 - 那他已经死了。
Not necessarily, major.
不一定，少校。
I refuse to mount a full-scale operation just to find out, colonel.
我不想发动一次大规模的军事行动，上校。
I need every single man I've got here, now!
我需要每一个现在已经在这里的人，我不想他们白白送命！
Sir, we don't need to mount a full-scale operation.
先生，我们不必进行一次大规模的军事行动。
Just give us two men.
我只需要两个人。
These officers are from headquarters. They're here to interrogate you.
这些军官是从总部来的，他们来审讯你们。
You reported five prisoners, major.
你报告说有5个犯人，少校。
Two of them tried to escape. They were shot.
有两个试图逃跑，被击毙了。
Maj. Schroeder is in the armoury, and I have told you before...
施罗德少校在军械库。我以前告诉过你们了……
...this area is out of bounds to you people, except Capt. Drazak.
……除了德拉扎克上尉，你们的人不能进入这个区域……
Kindly remove yourselves immediately...
……请你们立即离开……
...and if you can read, which I doubt, take a look at standing orders.
……如果你们认识字――我很怀疑这一点――去看一下张贴的命令。
There. You have made me burn the milk.
糟糕，我的牛奶被煮糊了。
So I did.
嗨，我说……
Let it burn.
……你还是让它糊了吧。
Open up.
开门。
Prisoners for Maj. Schroeder.
施罗德少校的囚犯被抓回来了。
You see, my colleague does not believe you are deserters.
你们看，我的同事不相信你们是逃亡者。
- The prisoners, sir. - What prisoners?
- 囚犯，长官。 - 什么囚犯？
I thought you said these men had been shot.
我记得你说他们被击毙了。
Right, gentlemen, shall we go?
好了，长官，我们可以走了吗？
No!
不！
This is not correct.
这么说可就不明智了。
Quick. Miller!
快，米勒!
Bring him. Open it.
把他带上。开门。
- Go. - Marko.
- 走。 - 马可。
Partisan bitch!
游击队婊子！
Always so kind to the men with burns.
总是跟大胡子好。
But they have no burns.
但他们没有大胡子。
The three Germans with the prisoners that escaped...
和跑掉战俘一起的那三个德国人……
...all shot in the back with machine pistols.
……都是被人用冲锋枪从背后打死的。
You killed them.
你杀了他们。
Good. Give me the hat.
好，把帽子给我。
Open. Open up.
开门，开门。
Open!
开门！
Milly.
米勒。
Weaver, don't stand there like an idiot. Let's get this truck moving.
维沃，别象个白痴似的站在那里，去开车，我们该走了。
She okay?
她好着吗？
Well, we'll drive as carefully as we can.
好吧，我们尽量把车开得稳一些。
Hey, you. I don't like the way you talk.
喂，你，我不喜欢你对我说话的态度。
- You what? - I don't like the way you talk to me.
- 你说什么？ - 我不喜欢你对我说话的态度。
This truck doesn't move till somebody tells me what's going on.
除非有人告诉我到底发生了什么，不然谁也别想走。
Now, look, you...
现在，你听着……
You bigtime officers have shafted me twice.
你是军官，但你耍了我两次了。
You tried to dump me in Italy, ran out on me back there.
在意大利你就想把我扔下，想背着我溜走。
You expect me to drive you like some chauffeur. Nobody tells me anything.
你还想让我给你们开车，但没有人告诉我任何事。
- You don't tell me what's going on. - I don't believe this.
- 你们从没告诉我到底发生了什么。 - 我不可能相信你。
Excuse me, but is your trouble that you want to be part of the team?
抱歉，自从你想成为我们中的一员时，你的麻烦就开始了。
I don't want to be a part of any lousy team.
我不想成为你们那糟糕的队伍中的一员。
I just want some equal consideration.
我仅仅希望有相同的知情权。
I don't think you'll get equal consideration...
我不认为你应该有什么知情权……
...from those people back there. Do you?
……你只不过是正在被宪兵押送的一个逃兵，不是吗？
I don't care if they're the U.S. Cavalry.
我才不管他妈的什么宪兵！
Nobody moves until somebody tells me what you're planning to do.
谁都别想走，除非有人告诉我你们的计划。
- We're going to blow up a bridge. - A bridge?
- 我们要去炸桥。 - 炸桥？
Whose bridge? Not me, I'm blowing up nothing.
谁的桥？那和我无关。
We are going to help the Partisans blow up a bridge...
我们要帮助游击队把桥炸掉……
...and then if we're very lucky, we can all go home.
……如果我们运气好，我们就能够回家。
- Is that a fact? - That's the general idea, sergeant.
- 真是这么回事？ - 就是这么回事，中士。
- That's why we came back for Miller. - Yeah, Miller.
- 看来这就是你们回来救米勒的原因。 - 是的，为救米勒。
You didn't give a mother-hunch about me.
你们对我没有一丁点儿的关心。
You came back for Miller, but you didn't come for me?
你们只不过为了米勒回来的，而不是为我。
No, we didn't.
是的，你说对了。
That's the first straight answer you've given me.
你总算对我说了一次真话。
I think the major's got a point, colonel.
我觉得少校还说了些实在话，上校。
They do look kind of mean, don't they?
看来有人来找咱们的麻烦了，是吧？
Don't stand there gaping like an idiot. Get in there and drive the truck!
那你还像白痴一样在那站着？还不快去开车！
All right.
好吧。
We'll have to do this another way.
得想别的办法了。
Get away from the truck.
都从车上下来。
Wait for my signal.
等我的信号。
Useful little insect, isn't he?
看来他真还有点用处。
- Keep an eye on him, Marko. - Miller, you are an incurable showoff.
- 马可，注意警戒。 - 米勒，你还真行啊！
Don't knock it, major. Don't knock it.
别逗他了，少校。
So now it works, huh, sergeant?
修好了吗，中士？
Well, these babies are a little temperamental sometimes.
是的，这个宝贝有时有点喜怒无常。
Like me.
和我一样。
Lescovar's confirmed my signals got through to London.
关于这个莱斯卡瓦，我通过伦敦做了进一步的确认。
Do you like that chap?
你觉得那个家伙怎么样？
- Who's that, Lescovar? - Yeah.
- 哪个？莱斯卡瓦？ - 对。
I haven't thought anything about him.
我还没把他搞明白。
- Knows his job, I suppose. - Yes, he does, doesn't he?
- 我猜也许他自己明白他在干什么。 - 也许吧。
All right, sergeant?
没问题吧，中士？
What do you think? Pretty straightforward, isn't it?
你怎么想的？大概很容易就能搞定吧？
Well, no, not exactly.
不，还说不准。
In fact, not by a long chalk.
事实上，不是那么容易。
I'd say you're flogging a dead horse there, old man.
我想说，你有点异想天开，老伙计。
- What are you trying to tell me? - Want to take a look?
- 你想告诉我什么？ - 想看看吗？
Are you kidding? I know every inch of that bridge.
你开玩笑吧？我了解那座桥的每一英寸。
Oh, yeah?
噢，是吗？
In that case, you'll have noticed how it's built into the living rock.
那么，你肯定注意到它是建在岩石上的了。
And how those main pilings are not just concrete, but 20 feet thick.
那些石墩可不是混凝土，它足有20英尺厚。
That's not forgetting...
别忘了……
I told you, London's dropping the same stuff we had before.
我告诉你，以前在伦敦已经研究过这一点。
Yes, I know what you're getting, but it's not gonna be enough.
是的，我知道你们肯定是有备而来，但是，那还不够。
- What do you mean, not enough? - You might just bend it a little...
- 你什么意思？不够？ - 可能，你只能使它摇晃两下而已……
...burn the paint work here and there.
……最多再让它着点小火。
But nothing that would seriously inconvenience the Jerries, I thought.
我想，除此之外，再干不了什么事。
Our experts have been studying that bridge, and they say it'll blow.
我们的专家研究过这座桥，他们说可以炸毁。
I don't know where you learned...
我不知道你为什么这么说……
...but I'm talking about the best engineers in the business.
……但我要说的是我们的专家都是桥梁建筑领域的权威人物。
Yes. They're probably experts at building things...
当然，他们在建筑方面都是专家……
...whereas I'm an expert at blowing them up.
……但是，在炸桥方面，我是专家。
Take it from me that one would need eight hours...
需要8小时的时间……
...to make a decent job of that bridge.
……完成炸桥的整项任务。
Eight hours?
8个小时？
Assuming, of course, the Jerries are kind enough to leave us in peace.
这还只是假定，前提是守敌很友善，会让我们安全撤离。
And maybe provide a few working lights.
而且，他们愿意用那些探照灯给我们照明。
You've seen those searchlights, have you? Well, l...
你看到那些探照灯了吗？我……
- Miller. - Sir.
- 米勒。 - 长官。
I think you've made your technical point.
我想你已经做出了很专业的说明。
Many thanks, sir.
多谢，长官。
If I weren't absolutely sure of my facts, I wouldn't be telling you this now.
如果我不是完全确定，我是不会向你们说这些的。
And you do understand, sir, I'm not exaggerating.
你一定要理解，长官，我不是在信口雌黄。
What would happen to the bridge if that central arch...
如果桥的中央支柱被……
...was suddenly hit by several million tons of water?
……几百万吨水突然冲击，桥会怎样？
- Water?
- 水？
I think we've been talking about the wrong target.
我认为我们一直在谈论一个错误的目标。
Remember that dam we passed up around the bend?
还记得我们曾经经过的那个水坝吗？
What kind of a dam? Where is it?
什么样的水坝？在哪儿？
Two and a half miles up the river.
离这两英里半的河的上游。
But, my dear chap, why didn't you say so before?
上帝！我亲爱的伙计，你怎么不早说？
Oh, I could do a tremendous job on a dam, yes.
哈哈，那我可就能在那个水坝上做点有意思的事了！
With a dam you've got natural elements working for you.
利用那个水坝，就可以借用大自然的力量为你工作了。
It's like an enormous bath. All you've got to do is pull the plug.
就像一个大浴缸，你要做的只是拔出那个塞子。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Come along, gentlemen.
来吧，先生们。
As a technician, I thought you might be interested in that dam, Milly.
米勒，看来那个水坝可以让你这位爆破专家大展身手了。
Get them outside for the dropping zone.
让他们准备空投场。
So the RAF drops the stuff and we blow the dam, right?
所以，皇家空军空投来装备，我们去炸掉水坝，对吗？
Right.
对。
Is it anything like Boulder Dam? Now, that baby's big, man.
它就象顽石坝（顽石坝――美国科罗拉多河上的大坝）？ 也许会更大些。
Wouldn't know, old boy.
你怎么知道这个，老伙计？
How often have you used this as a dropping zone?
你们曾用这种办法接受过空投吗？
Never.
从来没有。
The Germans see to that.
德国人会发现的。
We have to keep moving around.
我们没有更好的方法。
Makes sense.
合乎情理。
You think those two guys know anything about blowing a dam?
你认为那两个家伙要怎样炸掉水坝？
Oh, no, I shouldn't think they've got a clue.
哦，不，我觉得他们还没有什么好办法。
But never mind, old Weaver...
不过，也无所谓，维沃……
...we sergeants will see them through as usual.
……也许有人会给他们帮忙的。
- Right. - Hello.
- 但愿吧！ - 你好。
Ought you to be out and about? It's jolly cold.
你要出去干什么吗？外面可是很冷的。
Come on in, take a seat.
过来坐一会儿。
Thank you, but one thing I cannot do just yet is sit down.
谢谢，我唯一不能做的事就是“坐着”。
You're not staying for the fireworks? Bags of panic and blue lights.
你不来烤会儿火？暖和一阵儿？
No. I've seen too many airdrops.
不，我要去看一下空投情况。
They don't compare to a nice, warm bed.
你们在那慢慢享受吧。
Would you believe it? Right on time.
你看飞机会准点吗？
I don't believe it.
简直难以置信！
Poor bastards.
这些畜生！
This was no accident.
这不是意外发生的。
We've lost our last chance.
我们失去了最后的机会。
There is no question. We were betrayed.
没有任何疑问，我们被出卖了。
Aren't we always with Allied missions?
联合行动的时候，这样的事情总是发生。
Their security's a joke.
他们在拿安全问题开玩笑。
It doesn't matter.
是的，这没什么。
We do our part, and what do we get?
我们做我们该做的，可是我们得到了什么？
Twenty lives lost.
20个人死了！
- One of them... - It's past.
- 他们中有一个…… - 那都过去了。
Finished.
结束了。
All that matters now is that the Germans are marshalling their tanks.
最大的问题是德军的坦克部队就要到了……
They will cross the bridge tomorrow...
……他们后天会通过那座桥的……
...and there is nothing we can do to stop them.
……而且没有任何办法能够阻止他们。
And you four gentlemen have outstayed your usefulness.
你们四位留在这里已经发挥不了什么作用了。
You will be escorted back to the Allied military mission.
你们将被护送回盟军总部。
Out of harm's way?
我们就这样回去？
Sir...
长官……
...I could leave the Germans some very nasty surprises.
……我能给德国人一个噩梦般的惊喜的。
Thank you, sergeant.
谢谢，中士。
I think we have had enough surprises.
我想我们已经得到了足够多的惊喜了。
Capt. Lescovar, see that these gentlemen have an escort of two men.
莱斯卡瓦上尉，安排两个人护送这些绅士们离开。
If those chaps had just half the equipment of the Jerries...
如果能有一些装备……
...I could've made that dam look like a Swiss cheese.
……我准能把那水坝炸上天。
It's absolutely sickening.
真他妈让人丧气！
Do you think the Jerries will have that gear we need in their supply dump?
你想过没有，德军那里会有我们需要的东西。
Of course they would.
当然，他们有。
Lashings of HE, land mines, detonators, everything.
大量的高爆炸药、地雷、雷管，所有东西。
It's an absolute certainty.
绝对没有任何疑问。
Your escort, colonel.
你们的护送人，上校。
- I think you will find them reliable. - Okay, thank you.
- 他们很可靠。 - 当然，谢谢。
I think we're going to need rather more men than this, captain.
上尉，我认为我们需要的恐怕不是护送人。
My sergeant thinks that the Germans have the necessary equipment...
我的中士认为德国人那里有我们需要的装备……
...in their forward supply dump so that the colonel can blow the dam.
……用他们提供给我们的东西，我们会把水坝炸掉的。
That means you'd have to get into the marshalling yards at Mostar.
那意味着你们必须潜入德军基地。
None of you speak enough German.
你们中有谁会说德语吗？
You need me to help.
你们需要我的帮助。
Thank you, captain.
谢谢，上尉。
- You know, I could get shot for this. - Couldn't we all?
- 这一招太棒了。 - 当然。
You look real beautiful, you know that?
你看起来帅极了，你知道吗？
Yes, it's all right for you. You don't have to come with us.
是的，还是你走运，不用和我们一起去。
We'll be back in exactly 35 minutes, right?
我们35分钟后碰头。好了吗？
- Okay. - That's if the shop's open, old boy.
- 好了。 - 该德国人给我们“帮忙”了！
Pity they didn't teach you German at that school of yours.
真可惜，学校没有教你学会德语。
Instead of Latin? Perish the thought, old boy.
教的是拉丁语。现在学德语也不晚。
These any use to you?
这些对你有用吗？
No, tellermines is what we want.
没用，我们用地雷来干什么？
They look like dirty grey-green dinner plates.
它们看起来就像灰绿色的盘子。
Maybe they just haven't got any.
也许它们比盘子要厉害的多。
They have.
我相信是。
I wonder what happened to Barnsby and his truck.
我想知道巴纳比和他的卡车发生了什么事。
I've been asking myself the same question.
我已经问过自己同样的问题了。
Well, we can't just stand here like ducks in thunder.
好吧，我们不能象鸭子一样在这站着。
Over there. The railway wagon. Get the stuff in there till he comes.
那边，火车车厢，拿好东西，在那儿等他来。
Barnsby should have been here by now. Where the hell is he?
巴纳比现在应该在这里的。他死到哪儿去了？
Beautiful.
漂亮。
- They're just the job. - Not now, Milly.
- 这正是我该干的活。 - 不是现在，米勒。
Well, I'd rather do it now than in some ditch.
好了，我宁愿现在组装好，而不是躲在某条壕沟里的时候再忙活。
- How long? - Oh, about 10 minutes...
- 需要多久？ - 哦，大约10分钟……
...given peace and quiet.
……安静平和的10分钟。
These little sods can be temperamental.
这些小家伙脾气可是不怎么好！
The gubbins itself is harmless enough but aren't we all, until detonated.
这些小“玩具”威力不大，但它们能引爆威力大的炸药。
For a moment I thought we were off.
这么快我们的火车就开了！
Hey, where in the hell have they gotten to?
糟糕，他们这些该死的去哪里了？
You maniac.
你别乱发脾气。
What the hell are you doing here?
你明白你是来干什么的？
I'll go and have a look around, see if I can find them.
我去四处看看，看能不能找到他们。
- There he is. - Wait. I'll get him.
- 他们在那儿。 - 等等，我去叫他们。
- That's Lescovar. - Yeah.
- 那是莱斯卡瓦。 - 对。
- Where's Marko? - I don't know...
- 马可在哪儿? - 我不知道……
Bloody hell.
见鬼！
What's up now?
他在干什么？
Some great ape of a sergeant, he's sent Barnsby's truck away.
一个该死的中士让他把卡车开到那边去了。
Oh, no.
噢，不！
Sergeant.
中士。
Be quiet. Listen to me.
安静点，听我说。
There are two British commanders in that cattle truck behind me.
有两个英军突击队员在我身后那辆带蓬的车厢里。
I'm Col. Von Ingorslebon, Special Field Intelligence Group.
我是特别情报处的冯格里斯莱伯上校。
Stand still, idiot. Look natural.
站好，白痴，自然一点。
There is a third, an American colonel...
第三个是一个美军上校……
...in the truck which you just sent away.
……在你刚才打发走的那辆卡车里。
I want to take them all together.
我要把他们一网打尽。
- What's Lescovar doing? - He's shooting him some kind of story.
- 莱斯卡瓦在干什么？ - 他正在给那个德国兵讲故事吧。
Go and assemble a squad of armed men. Quickly and quietly.
去召集一队人来抓他们。快点，安静点！
And keep them out of sight.
别让他们发觉。
Then report back to me. Understand?
然后回来向我报告。明白？
Good old Lescovar. Best line-shooter in the Balkans.
莱斯卡瓦，巴尔干最好的吹牛专家！
All right, you guys, let's...
好了，伙计们，我们……
Oh, man.
哦，伙计。
The sacks, get them up here quick.
我们赶快离开这里。
- You picked a fine time to do this. - Sling out my suitcase, will you?
- 你选了个好时间干活呀！ - 把手提箱递出来，好吗？
You trying to screw up this operation? We're behind schedule already.
你在耽误时间，我们已经比计划延迟了。
- How did you get here? - I've been through that already.
- 你怎样过来的？ - 我用自己的办法过来的。
Help me get this stuff loaded and get it on the truck.
帮我把东西装好，然后放到卡车上。
- Right, Miller? - Right, all set.
- 好了，米勒? - 对，全好了。
Let's go. Easy.
我们走。
Hold it.
拿好。
It's that man again.
又是那个人。
I'll take care of him. Close the door.
我来应付他。关上门。
They are all yours, sergeant. Bring the squad.
他们都是你的了，中士，把你的人带过来。
All clear?
可以瓮中捉鳖了。
Give them a moment to get out of sight.
太简单了。
That fool, Marko, must have given himself away.
愚蠢的马可！自己想办法逃吧！
I don't know how.
我真不知道是怎么回事。
How in the hell are we gonna get back across the river?
该死的！我们该怎么办？
I mean, where are we going?
我的意思我们这是去哪儿？
Berlin, I shouldn't wonder.
就算去柏林我也不会觉得奇怪。
Sarajevo.
萨拉热窝。
That's where the train goes.
那是这列火车的目的地。
No stops.
中途不停。
I'm sorry about Marko.
我为马可感到难过。
Thank you.
谢谢。
It's a risk we all take.
他牺牲自己救了我们大家。
He was a brave man and a good friend.
他是一个勇敢的人，也是一位好朋友。
Pity he got careless.
可惜他太不小心了。
Do you think that big sergeant spotted him as a Partisan?
你认为那个中士认出他是游击队员？
I can't buy that.
我不知道。
The sergeant wasn't that bright.
那个中士还没有那么聪明。
He saluted you, you're wearing a corporal's uniform.
他向你敬礼，而你穿的是下士的制服。
That doesn't rate a salute in the German army.
在德国军队里，可不是规定中士向下士敬礼的。
Not in anybody's army.
在任何军队里都不会是这样的。
Why do you think he saluted you, Lescovar?
你怎么看他向你敬礼这事，莱斯卡瓦？
Perhaps he recognized my natural superiority.
也许在他眼里我看起来象个长官。
Yes, perhaps.
是的，有可能。
You say this train goes to Sarajevo, no stops?
你说这列火车开往萨拉热窝，中途不停？
Yeah.
是的。
But I noticed on the map that we pass within a half a mile of the dam.
从地图上看，一英里半后我们就会经过那个水坝。
Strange you didn't bother to mention that.
奇怪的是，你没有提到这一点。
Now, what's all this about?
那么，这些能说明什么？
Some fool of a sergeant salutes me...
一个愚蠢的德军中士向我敬礼……
...and I forget to mention that we pass near the dam.
……还有我忘记了提我们会从水坝附近经过。
And a little while ago, you said that Marko must have given himself away.
还有，你还说过马可“自己想办法逃吧”。
I don't think he gave anything away...
他是根本逃不出来的……
...except his life.
……因为他当时已经被打死了。
What did you give away, Lescovar?
你出卖了什么，莱斯卡瓦？
You think I'm a traitor, is that it?
你猜想我是叛徒，是吧？
I don't think, I know.
我不是猜想，是确信。
I've always known.
我早就确信无疑。
I just couldn't prove it.
只不过我需要证据。
You're Nicolai.
你是尼古拉。
You're the man who blew us in Greece.
你就是在希腊神秘消失的那个人。
Thank you, colonel.
谢谢，上校。
I've done your job.
我做了你该做的事。
You help me do mine.
你也给我帮过忙的。
Oh, crikey.
哦，上帝！
It's lit like a Christmas tree.
那桥看起来就象一棵圣诞树。
Dawn's around 5:30.
5：30天就亮了。
Gives us an hour to get in...
我们大约还有一个小时的时间……
...half-hour to set the charges and 20 minutes to get clear.
……半小时安放炸药，20分钟撤离。
What you need, sir, is a little diversion, isn't it?
你需要什么，长官，来场焰火晚会？
- What am I supposed to do with this? - Oh, I don't know.
- 这些用来干什么？ - 哦，我也不知道。
Try and imagine you're a dog.
给我们的朋友送个见面礼吧。
Oh, for heaven's sake. On the road, man, on the road!
噢，看在上帝的份上！放到路上，伙计，放到路上去！
Hallelujah!
哈利路亚！（哈利路亚――表示感谢、赞美上帝的意思。）
Just unroll it and string it out.
展开，拉过去。
Come on, blackie.
来呀，黑鬼！
Come on.
来吧！
Hey. You bleed red blood, eh, blackie?
嗨，你流出的血怎么也是红色的，黑鬼？
Here.
这儿。
Right here.
就是这儿。
You all right?
你没事吧？
Come on, blow, damn it! Blow!
快呀！见鬼！他们怎么还没出来？！
Give them a chance. They'll be here in a minute.
再给他们点时间，一会儿他们就出来了！
If they'd been caught, we'd have heard the alarm go off.
如果他们被抓住了，我们就会听到警报响的。
How long do we make the fuse?
引信定多长时间？
They're Germans, they're gonna be punctual.
他们是德国人，他们是很守时的。
Usually are.
历来如此。
We've run out of time.
我们没有时间了。
Twenty seconds?
20秒？
What do you say?
你说怎么样？
It's your decision, colonel.
你决定，上校。
I'm asking you.
我在问你。
Twenty seconds sounds about right, then we won't have so far to run.
看来应该是20秒，但我们跑不了多远。
It would have been nice to see that bridge go, huh?
看着桥垮倒可是够开心的，对吧？
Yes, wouldn't it?
是的，怎么不是呢？
All been very interesting, though, hasn't it?
一切都那么有趣，是吧？
Yes.
当然。
It didn't do a goddamn thing! Nothing!
他们干了些什么狗屁事！什么都没发生！
Miller! That useless git!
混帐米勒！没有成功！
- It didn't... - What?
- 它没有…… - 什么？
- It didn't work! - I know it didn't work!
- 没有奏效！ - 我知道没有奏效！
- Well, let's get out of here! - Yeah, let's get out of here.
- 算了，我们从这儿出去！ - 好，出去！
When I catch that little perisher, I'll wring his useless neck!
该死的米勒！都是他的主意！看我抓住他不掐断他的脖子！
Nothing!
不会有别的了！
We've been through all this, and nothing!
我们费尽千辛万苦干到这一步，竟然一无所获！
Nothing but:
的确！狗屁都没有！
You can't expect an enormous volcano with three tiny bags of explosives.
你不能指望那么一个庞然大物能被三个小小的炸药包给炸上天……
You have to let nature take her course.
……你必须顺其自然……
Give it time, it'll work.
……给点时间，就会有变化的。
If I were you, I'd get out of here fast!
如果我是你，我会以最快的速度离开这里！
- You son of a bitch! - I told you, it's only a matter of waiting.
- 看那些狗娘养的德国人！ - 我告诉过你，只需耐心等待那么一会儿。
You cute little son of a bitch! You did it! Come here.
你这个可爱的混球！你真地做到了！来这儿。
You did it! You did it! You cute little son of a... You did it!
你做到了！你做到了！ 你这个聪明的龟儿子……你做到了！
Why, you limey genius, I love you!
太棒了！你这个该死的天才英国佬，我太爱你了！
Steady on, old Weaver, steady on.
小心，老伙计，克制一点。
You did it!
你做到了！
Miller, you horrible little man...
米勒, 你真是一个“可恶的混蛋”……
...you knew that was gonna be a slow-motion explosion.
……你知道我当时看到爆破没有反应的时候怎么想吗？
You deliberately didn't tell me, did you?
你故意不告诉我，是吧？
I didn't want to bore you with technical detail.
我不想用技术细节去烦你。
I thought it might be a bit over your head.
我觉得那有点超过你的理解能力。
What happened to you?
你怎么啦？
He bit me in all the excitement.
他让我兴奋得不得了。
But damn it to hell, we did it, colonel, we did it!
我们到底把那桥送下了地狱，我们赢了， 上校，我们做到了！
Yes, we did, sergeant. We did!
是的，中士，我们做到了！
And a merry Christmas.
就像过圣诞节一样开心！
Yes, gentlemen, we did it.
当然，先生们，我们干得不错。
But before...
但是，在……
...we can start awarding ourselves Victoria Crosses...
……我们能给自己发维多利亚十字勋章……
...and Congressional Medals of Honor and so on...
……还有国会荣誉勋章……
...and so forth and such like...
……诸如此类，等等之前……
...I think I'd better point out that, one: We're on the wrong side of the river.
……我想我们必须先明白：第一，我们在河的另一边。
That two: We have no hope whatsoever of rejoining the Partisans.
第二，我们没有什么希望回到游击队那里。
And that three:
第三……
This neck of the woods will soon be crawling with bad-tempered Germans.
……很快就会有漫山遍野的德国人来找我们。
And four:
还有第四……
I don't think that our little genius, Sgt. Miller there...
……我不认为我们天才的米勒中士还能……
...has even got a box of matches left in his suitcase.
……从他那神奇的手提箱里给我们拿出 什么能解决以上难题的新鲜玩意。
And so, therefore, I think we can take it, gentlemen...
所以，我想我们能断定，先生们……
...that we are going to have a very long walk home.
……我们只能走很长的路回家去。